

Fairfax, VA 856-745-7765 ajschmidt.com me@ajschmidt.com linkedin.com/in/ajschmidt3

BIOGRAPHY

Full Stack JavaScript professional perched on the bleeding edge of web development. Expertise in React, CSS, HTML, Node, Express, and accompanying tools like Webpack, npm, and Git. Enjoys building automation tools that help teams operate more efficiently (ask me about *CardBot* and *Grev*). Passion for technology highlighted by superior leadership and extraordinary personal initiative.

EDUCATION

B.S. ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

Jun. 2016 GPA - 3.46

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS (SASS), JavaScript (React, Node, Express, Jest), PHP, Python

TOOLS/LIBRARIES: AWS, Docker, Git, Jenkins, npm, Webpack, WordPress, Vagrant

EXPERIENCE

CAPITAL ONE: Sr. Software Engineer

Jul. 2018 - Present

Maintain AngularJS site platform while building new Angular 7 platform. Write E2E tests to ensure site functions as expected. Built GitHub application (in Node) with 100% test coverage to automatically label pull requests with information from Jira. Interview new team prospects. Mentor coworkers in all aspects of JavaScript. Maintain CI/CD pipelines in Jenkins.

CARFAX: Product Developer

Apr. 2018 - Jul. 2018

Rebuilt Vehicle History Report landing page from scratch using modern tooling and practices. Created a custom webpack configuration to minify/concatenate CSS and JS, transpile JS, compress all images, cachebust assets, and compile Pug into HTML. Rebuild & redesign resulted in +\$2mil yearly increase.

RECOVERY BRANDS: Front-End Developer II

Jan. 2018 - Apr. 2018

Front-End Developer I

Jan. 2017 - Jan. 2018

Updated and maintained Recovery Brands' 20+ WordPress properties. Built new sites from InVision mock-ups using webpack, SASS, npm, and git. Wrote WordPress custom-post-type plugin to allow staff members to be easily updated on recoverybrands.com. Created git hooks to automate Jira task updates. Authored *grev* npm package to streamline code review process by using Node and GitHub, Slack, and Jira APIs.

LOCKHEED MARTIN: Intern & Systems Engineer

Mar. 2015 - Nov. 2016

Served on team of 10 analysts that used Matlab simulations to perform gap analyses, model-driven tests, sensitivity studies and concept exploration. Conducted >1,000 complex missile simulations on weekly basis; analyzed and summarized findings using PowerPoint and visual plots. Served as operations point person and peer mentor.

FREELANCE: Web Developer

Mar. 2012 - Present

Create responsive websites for clients with frameworks like WordPress and Express. Minify and concatenate static assets with webpack. Employ services like Clicky or Google Analytics for traffic data. Implement Cloudflare's free CDN for an additional speed boost. Deploy final product on shared hosting (Siteground) or VPS (DigitalOcean).



Fairfax, VA 856-745-7765 ajschmidt.com me@ajschmidt.com linkedin.com/in/ajschmidt3

PERSONAL PROJECTS

WPBenchmarks Aug. 2018 - Present

WPBenchmarks posts daily speed test results for popular shared WordPress hosts. The front-end is built with <u>Gatsby</u> (a React framework) and the back-end is powered by Node. <u>K6</u> is used to perform the speed tests and the results are uploaded to AWS's DynamoDB for consumption by the front-end. The site also uses <u>Highcharts</u> to display the test results and SVG animations for showing server locations. - https://www.wpbenchmarks.live/

VOLUNTEER WORK

HopeCam Jan. 2019 - Present

Assist HopeCam in their efforts to connect children with cancer to their classroom via webcams. Perform administrative tasks in the office. Draft emails to send to HopeCam's newsletter subscribers.

Code Apprentice Sept. 2018 - Dec. 2018

Mentored a high school senior on topics of web development via video chat over the course of a semester. Covered web fundamentals including HTML, CSS, and JavaScript and continued on to address webpack, Express, and MongoDB. Student's final project was a site called ClubFinder that served as a directory for all of the extracurricular clubs that his school offers to students.